Port forwarding offers a way in which one
can use a specific port as a means to connect
to a specific device within a network.
Take, for example, someone wanting to remote
into their home computer through their home
internet connection, which is a public facing
router.
The problem is that the home computer probably
does not have a public IP address.
However, we can use a port number to forward
the connection from the router to the PC.
This is known as port forwarding and I will
open this feature on a router.
Then, I will select Add Port Forward and then
Continue.
I will then set my laptop as the connecting
device and enter port 3389, the Remote Desktop
port, as the port to use for this connection.
Then I will select Next and the port forward
has been added.
What is very important to do is if a port
forwarding is no longer needed, remove it,
because leaving this here can risk an intruder
into this device.
To remove this, I will select Edit, Delete
this Port Forward, and then Delete.